# Abdullah Alshenaifi

#### **ELECTRONICS ENGINEER**

Abdullah@aashenaifi.com +966554337765 aashenaifi.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Electronics enthusiast with hands-on experience in the Internet of Things and 3D printing. Co-owner of Alamat Robotics, where I engineered electronics for a myriad of robotic projects. Teaching programming and electronics courses at Tuwaiq Academy, mentor students in project-based learning and international competitions. I look forward to putting into action the skills and knowledge acquired and bringing some innovation into the work environment.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

September 2019- Present

Co-Owner, Alamat Robotics

Engineered electronics for various robotics projects, including designing and 3D printing robotic eyes and developing a robotic arm.

August 2021 - Present

Electronics Engineering Volunteer, Tawasal Association for Assistive Technologies for People with Disabilities

Designed assistive electronic circuits and IoT systems for people with disabilities and installed these systems in homes.

July 2024 - August 2024

**Instructor**, Tuwaiq Academy

Teaching Arduino programming and electronics to junior students, developing tailored curriculum, mentoring in project-based learning, and organizing practice sessions to prepare them for international competitions.

## **EDUCATION**

September 2021 - November 2023

Electronics and System Engineering, Technical College of Riyadh

- Bachelor's degree
  - Assistant Supervisor of Technical Talents Center: Supervised trainees, managed video and photography, organized events, delivered technical training, and performed AV work.

**Graduation Project**: A water monitoring system for shared apartments and houses, using Internet Of Things (IOT), 3D printing, and data analysis.

### **SKILLS**

Soldering SMT and THT 3D Modeling and Printing PLC programming

Design implementation Problem-solving Arduino Programming

Troubleshooting Microsoft Office Team Collaboration